Jon Wolfe

Fullstack Developer



About

- Columbus Ohio 43016
- jonathanwolfe5@gmail.com
- (704) 301-7568
- □ jonathanwolfe.github.io
- in in/jonathanwolfe5
- **y** JonWolfe
- O Jon_Wolfe

Frontend Development

Master

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Riot.js

Gulp

Ember

Polymer

Next.js

React

Backend Development

Intermediate

Python

Node.JS

MySQL

Summary

Frontend Developer of 13 years turned Fullstack when Node.JS exploded in popularity. Specializing in converting legacy systems/apps to modern toolsets and practices, as well as full rebuilds when a new architecture is wanted. Currently thinking very seriously about creating a new UI language that brings concepts like reactivity and state management flows similar to mobx or redux into the core (RIP to my free time if I decide to do this).

Experience

PigKnows

Lead Developer

Primary developer on a full stack Next.JS client and node-based API for managing pig farms and the animals lifecycles throughout. Finished by building a feed ordering featureset to create rations and budgets, track order history, and notify supplier of new orders.

- Converted a large portion of both projects to Typescript
- Added 4 third-party integrations to sync data between for customers who used multiple vendors
- Created a feed tracking and ordering system to send orders to mills and veterinarians
- Refactored critical custom keyboard controls resulting in a 10x rendering time reduction

04/2015 - 12/2019

12/2019 - 04/2021

Software Architecture

Intermediate

Terraform

AWS

Nginx

Node.JS

Linux

Languages

English German (Native Speaker) (Beginner)

Interests

Computer Programming

Video Game Programming
IDE / Text Editors
UI Programming
Languages/Libraries

Video Game Playing

JRPGs

League of Legends

Competitive Shooters

Trivia

How It's Made How Do They Do It Unwrapped

Reading / Writing

Manga

High Fantasy Novels

Sci-fi thrillers

Techno Dystopia/Utopia Thrillers

Advanced/Senior Software Developer

Refactor and replace a legacy prototype shipped to production with a modern, web-components based UI for Mindsphere's "Big Data" Analytics product, Product Intelligence. Built with Polymer 1 (web components v0), sass, and lots of reusable and composable components that are the being used as the base line for quality for the rest of Mindsphere UI.

- Refactored a multi-million dollar application to modern standards
- Improved UI performance by 7x
- Decreased page weight by 1-4mb (down to 200kb-1mb depending on the page)

Socialtopias

02/2015 - 02/2016

Frontend Developer

Initially brought on to salvage the original product of the same name which was a large scale social network intent on bringing people together at real life physical locations and helping them plan their future endeavors and plans. The app also helped business to connect and identify their clientele and offer them much more direct engagement. After stabilizing the project and fixing all bugs, a mostly comprehensive overhaul was done which drastically improved the application's responsiveness, features, and usability.

- Salvaged a completely broken and unfinished large-scale product
- Greatly improved existing feature set
- Eliminated some 500+ bugs
- Rewrote most of the app to be much simpler and more capable of reuse

The Idea People

12/2014 - 02/2015

Frontend Developer

Was tasked with handling the company's agency work while most of it's developers where engaged in building the Socialtopias App (see next company). After failing to complete the project and losing the contract, I was let go for monetary reasons.

- Built modern Wordpress templates with fully responsive capabilities
- Helped teach co-workers how to use Git and other tools

Mythic

07/2014 - 10/2014

Frontend Developer - Consultant

Maintained many existing company and business sites as well implemented new features and fixes for those. Crafted new products for their budding digital presence.

- Integrated new online payment platform and interactions
- Constructed a complete real estate platform with fully responsive elements

Fire Studios

01/2005 - 01/2013

Owner and Sole Developer

Owned and operated a small freelance company that covered both back-endDate PHP work as well as front-endDate contracts (HTML, CSS, JS). Outsourced any excess work and managed those contractors.

- Worked across several languages like JS & PHP
- Worked with various size companies and the semi-local University of South Carolina
- Where I honed most of my development skills



Volunteer

Restoration Ranch

Volunteer

Helped dig troughs for the water pipes to the building



Education

* References

through noise and identify an optimal path to a technical solution. He is consistent in his output, and can be relied upon to produce at a steady, predictable pace. This is in regards to not only his work ethic, but also his ability to move through previously un-encountered technical challenges. Give Jon a codebase in which he has not previously worked, and he will sort it out and be producing with it in very short order. He is very aware of current and emerging technologies, but applies them to solutions in a sensible manner (rather than using personal interest as a primary motivator).

Nick Hendricks - PigKnows

Jon is one of the best developers I had pleasure to work with. He is passionate about what he is doing and never cuts corners.

Never afraid to raise his concerns and propose the best solution for given problem. I have learned a lot from him and think he is going to be a great addition to any team.

Yury Katko - Siemens

It's rare that you come across standout talent and mind like Jon's. I hired Jon as a front end web developer and he is quite skilled in this area. Jon always has a handle on the latest available technologies and tools and went beyond his role as developer to also help out other team members with other aspects of our tech stack outside the front end web application development arena. He is also masterful with git version control tools, which helped a lot as our project was ramping up and we were creating the internal tools and processes to get things done. Jon is punctual and reliable too. Jon would be good on any web app team.

Corky Kaericher - Socialtopias

"

Every bit the developer he claimed to be and then some.

— Sara Garces Roselli - Mythic